um
so we had a conversation
earlier in the week
um and he described how
the kind of the miracle of a Samus and
Buddha in the sense that they don't have
any signpost
say um
um
how far to go in terms of discovering
the middle way so so you get to this
point and then you don't go any further
um so
so
wondering if I could just give my
interpretation of how I see that the
meaning of it one way of describing that
um in relation to for example patitas
with this this is
um
so um
I have no say in
the in being in a body or breathing or
being in a posture at all feeling
or no fundamental intention yeah so so
there's I find myself in in this
situation where these phenomena
um
are present
and then
um
this sort of self this sense of self
on top of these these things which are
not self which are not in which I have
no say over
[Music] um
there is this sort of
wanting pleasure and not wanting pain
and sort of yeah distracting
from the the um
um pleasurability of of of
of of
the lack of control I have over my
existence or existence
um
and so so the point at which
so so the point at which
this sort of the middle way is is
basically
seeing this responsibility for
craving yeah the the time responsible
for that for this sense of self this this
that for this sense of self this this
ignorance or this this um perversion
but at the same time yeah there are
phenomena which are are broader or more
General that are
still present that there is still this
experience but
um
would it so to
put it concisely would it be kind of
like coming down to seeing what you can
be responsible for yeah and what you
cannot be responsible for
and the the difference between the two
which sounds like something quite simple
but it turns out yeah so yeah easy yeah
so you're not trying to get rid of these
things which you're not responsible for
you're not trying to
yeah interfere with that yeah but you are
interfere with that yeah but you are
trying to decide what you are
responsible for
yeah but you are still subjected
things you're not responsible for
and the middle way
should often escape from that
such as sickness aging death
so
how does the middle way offer the escape
from that yep obviously started by
recognizing responsibility
so as long as you think the suffering is
caused by things in the world or objects of
by things in the world or objects of
your attention and so on you won't see
what the problem is so take
responsibility then you might get to
understand that the craving is a bit of
suffering um but how then what to do in terms of
um but how then what to do in terms of
so in terms of that middleweight
practice they would then
they would then
free you even from things you are not
responsible for but you are subjected to
and burdened by
anyone I mean
because it's not as simple as saying you
know there's things that you're totally
not responsible for but you're subjected
to the reason that the middle way frees
you even from those is that you are kind
of indirectly responsible for I suppose
maintaining or
um
feeding the possibility of being
subjected even to those things so if
that's how we Define it now then is
there anything that you're completely
not responsible for
because that's how we started
that would be relevant somehow
I would say no yeah yeah because as he
said they need to recognize what you are
responsible no I'm just saying because I
think the way you were describing is
kind of things you're not responsible
for meant things that you have
indirectly responsible for yeah but
since we more accurately Define it now I
think we have to say that then things
are not responsible for you're not
responsible for and they wouldn't be
burning you so yeah sickness aging and
death if that's how we call it now is
something you are indirectly responsible
for if it bothers you if if you're
subjected too so I'll then
what would be the the way out of that
I actually had a
well a kind of a there was this even to
put it as a simulator occurred to me in
regards to this
how it's how it seems is that
if you think of like it's like a burning
fire that is that is burning you with
this heats the common sense
automatic reaction is to I need to burn
sorry the reaction to it automatically
or immediately with common sense with
everybody is I need to put out this
Burning Fire I need to put something on
it put water on it sure do something to
put it out
and that's
the thing what you realize with the
middle way is that actually
it's everything I put on this fire
is actually adding to the fire and the
reason that I'm burned by this burning
fire that it's there in the first place
is as a result of me over all of the
past I all I've been doing all my life
is adding to the fire basically
basically inadvertently so all I have to do is
inadvertently so all I have to do is
actually not
but keep fueling this fire
and then not only will I know that all I
have to do is not keep fueling the fire
and it will have to go out eventually
but even then because I don't go to the
fire to put something on it and REM and
try to put it out I realized that
actually already that is directly removing a huge
already that is directly removing a huge
weight of suffering because when you go
to the fire you get burnt it's something
I wanted to get out but when you don't
go to it you don't get burnt yeah yeah
so you would see the results here and
now in that way
the trick obviously now is to
or rather the next step will begin to
Define what would constitute not fueling
the fire because people can
practice not fueling of the fire that's
still actively fueling it in other words
when they say I'm not feeling the fire
they're doing it in a way that it's
actually fueling the fire
so that's not just a question of simply
putting stuff and abstaining from
everything that will make the fire go
away you know you gotta find that middle
way because abstaining from if you
abstain from too much if you denounce
too much too many things in a way that
uh just doesn't still see where the line
of responsibility is that's another way
of fueling the fire so that's the whole
kind of the two ways of indulgent you
know sensuality blame the world trying
to get rid of it so on and then the
other one denying and trying to sort of
like you know cancel everything
internally and externally both would be
equally burning
so then the middle way would come
obviously as we say credential training
as I should say
but again more specifically how that
non-fueling of the fire
culminate that you know now you cannot be burnt
that you know now you cannot be burnt
finished
noticed in this life but done
what would be the measure of that
success
we said it last time yeah I was thinking
that it's probably the most obvious way
to say it would be with the anata that
there is complete number because it is
yeah and obviously there's a right way going
and obviously there's a right way going
of going about it and that's what we
keep talking about you know you're not
trying to get rid of things you know
blaming things you know trying to sort
of
mechanically just do certain practices
and then hope that these experiences
will come on their own they need to be
understood on the basis of what you
already are but nevertheless yeah that
should be the goal so it's not just
about uh enduring and putting up and not
uh enduring and putting up and not
acting out and so on it's about that as
a basis but then
so that then the inside correct inside
of of true anata
can be established
can be discerned recognized and then
cultivated and and brought to
fulfillment so you know like we mentioned before in
so you know like we mentioned before in
the previous talk petition and so on and
it does boil down to that simultaneous
principle but if you read the suit as
you see it's kind of
quite often described in many different
ways as you mentioned last time I think
we're done before uh you know whether
it's like the the the food for the thing
that is present it depends on food would
exemplify the simultaneous relationship
or like you know with the present
condition this is the present result
so the point is to understand that it's
not something that I will cause an
effect but on like things that depend
one on the other so as you said when you
started when you open this up you kind
of you said oh this is like the sense of
self and so on and then things that are
not kind of in your control that are
kind of the
inescapable limits of your situation
those are the bases you can't go outside
of those you can't go outside of the
body the posture the perceptions and so
on
so then
that whole sense of self it's not enough
to just say oh this is not mine
not I am not myself I mean if you're a
noble disciple that's yeah you need to
do not just say it but keep applying
that attitude to that phenomenon of self
that's what we'll encourage monks to do
but in order to do that first you need
to see that sense of self and then you
need to see that sense of self as not
yours not being independent on a master
existing outside of the that in this
capability of your situation
so it's really not so much about
uh finding an answer to the question of
myself and not self and so on it's
really about the mental practice of
whatever that sense of self is whichever
way it endures to see it as second as
within as fully enclosed within this
inescapable limits of this situation in
the body posture you've got an enduring
feeling and so on
and then sustain it oh what's next no
that's that's it because you will fall
from it you know you know and and
obviously you won't even do it rightly
first time but if you know that it's
supposed to
so you're not supposed to remove the
sense of self
You're simply supposed to
set it up through your attention and you
only serve that attention
as
impossible to own while it is still
there so the sense of self and you can all
so the sense of self and you can all
like recall your sense of self now as we
speak it has to be there doesn't matter
what it is then exemplified through a
clear thought or ambiguous a sense of I
am sitting here that I am it's obviously
not this physical thing
but is that gratuitous separation that's
been maintained to desire agree
diversion delusion and so on so the
question is not to like
um as I said remove or ignore the sense
itself but not to kind of try to force
it either into oh it's not self it's not
self it's like this it's like the floor
it's like these branches of the super
Dimension no if you want to send it
sense of self-induring and there is a
situation of this body perception sounds
maltest touches enduring
so if that's too complex you could
simply say oh well okay there is there
is this situation on the basis of this
body for whatever it is to whatever extent it
for whatever it is to whatever extent it
is and there is this sense of self
do you see that
like forget about okay so this guy first
this is within the other this is not
mine just that can come into play later
but for now do you see your sense of
self-induring simultaneously on a
different plane
from your five senses and your thoughts
and everything else
so
so here in Yonder as my situation of
this you know Infinite Space so to speak
and my sense of self kind of
perpendicular to that simultaneously
here
because at any given time
doesn't matter what you're engaged with
somebody to ask you who are you or
something you would have that there
so but the point is to not bother or not
spend too much on trying to Define who
you are or who this I am is or what is
to seeing and during he's seeing it
enduring there as this weird ambiguous
concept phenomenon that can never be
kind we can never put your finger on it
but it's always there
the point is to not even bother trying
to put a finger on it but to not lose
the sight of it as something that is
always there
see as much as the
your body your current posture your
feeling your perception is the kind of
that as you said the basis of that
inescapability of this situation here in
Yonder well the image of the self or the
notion of the self is equally the other
end of Uranus capability of your situation
of Uranus capability of your situation
you are not outside of that image either
so when you recognize that these two
things doesn't they don't even know about you
doesn't they don't even know about you
so your body your situation is there on
its own and then you realize what this
phenomenon is there on its own
pretty much as a result of this here
that it's on its own
but of course a sense of self being more
ambiguous more kind of in the background
um less palpable less measurable
always naturally kind of gets gets gets
bundled with that Aroma of subjectivity
and mine and I am because it's kind of
you know always it's always above all of
this it's always outside all of this
it's always the observable of this well
it doesn't matter what kind of Observer
it is and how it might feel the only
reason it can be an observer is because
there's this to be observed
if there is nothing to be observed
Observer will not be self-aware of
there's nothing there's nothing defining
it
so it's to recognize that it's not the
Observer comes first and this comes
second or this comes first second notes
with the Observer this is the observed
it's really observed felt perceived
taste touched the Observer is
so
without I mean you know if your mind is
calm within this principle and you have
room to move without sort of falling off
from it so to speak from this type of
samadhi sure you can then think about
various particular aspects of this
relationship but fundamentally the point is simply to
but fundamentally the point is simply to
get very used to
having a sense of self-endure
simultaneously with having this
experience endure as it changes and you
speak and you move and you stand up and
so on
two simultaneous things at the same time
and as we said before
if that becomes something you just see
normally because you've been looking for
it
that self-centered one point of view at
the same time will be undermined simply
through that
and as I was saying to you maybe to you
before the other day that's how people
practiced on account of Faith Sada in
the Buddha like they had minimal
instruction and it's sometimes puzzling you read the
and it's sometimes puzzling you read the
students and somebody just had faith and
became another hunt as a result of it
people would think oh they're the faith
on the level of the guru is the greatest
and I'm so devotional so the
enlightenment will happen to me because
you know I'm I'm such a good follower
but no actually this is what it means
means they understood this basic
principle they haven't understood any
single implication afterwards they
didn't need to but they stuck to the
very basic recognition with this disease
which is there was no teacher summer
party you know the person didn't yeah
sure exactly we eat the whole thing it
did it yeah he just
as they were cases oh the master got him
explains the the condition conditions of
everything that has arisen now you can
translate that in a manner of cause and
effect but you can also understand that
the head to the the condition the basis
means like Okay so Master Gautama
understands or teaches the undermining
of the sense itself the undermining of
one through having two simultaneously
present and somebody understands that and sees
and somebody understands that and sees
it so not just oh that's a lovely idea I
have faith in it oh see oh this sense of
self and this oh what if I stick to this
and contemplate it are the faith in
Mastic Ultima they were so inspiring to
see they actually did it and as a result of
they actually did it and as a result of
it even without bothering or making
effort towards kind of more specific
clarifications and permutations they
they arrived at the final goal of this
passion because that is what's all is
needed with this this is
without this this would not be
thus anything else that you assumed is
in between
it will just evaporate especially
anything else that you assumed is mine
and and the pertaining to the core of
that subjectivity they will just just
vanish it will just sort of dissipate
and that's one of those other
contemplation like recognizing that this
body I
this situation of mine that I'm enclosed
with and so on oh it's dependent it's
sitting upon food having food
having to eat these external things as a
whole just that the phenomenal food is
why this body is alive no other reason
you take that away
the body will not be able to remain
alive
or like the uh atmosphere and breathing
like the oxygen well the element of air
sure the four Great elements they are in
a particular Arrangement that your body
is made of
so you just need to add a bit more of
one remove a bit more of the other
and that's it you won't be anymore
that's all it takes and there was that
reflection of recollecting you know the
great Earth and the mountain and you
know that they would crumble and get
that they would crumble and get
destroyed and broken
what is then to be said for this sort of
little tiny
and they lived on top of it it's just
inconceivable to immunos but again it's
not you can think of it in that linear way
you can think of it in that linear way
or this will be destroyed thus I will be
destroyed no no you see the Earth as
this and you see your body as this is as a
and you see your body as this is as a
result of that Earth simultaneously
present so if that earth that is
simultaneously the necessary condition
for your entire existence changes
that's it you don't need to know what
will happen to the or rather witness
what will happen to what this is in my
body you will immediately feel it so and
that what you feel is what anata is
so if you cultivate that on the basis of
pre-sense restraint and Solitude because
otherwise you're just going to be
dwelling with anxiety in and out
and not and trying to get rid of it as
well with yourself
but if you have been cultivated in the
gradual training beforehand this will
actually be liberating
that undermining the sense of self
in their directly simultaneous manner
will feel like a relief from the burden
from the tension from the presence
and that's why the noble AFL path is the
way for that to become your experience
established not just you know this this
technique it's not entirely so your
actions your intentions your livelihood
all of that built up is contributing
towards sustaining this up until it
cannot be otherwise
do not tell
so would it be correct to say that
it's important to for example if you
want to contemplate the element of Earth
in regard to the body
to do that while seeing
the body as where your sense of self is
if you know what I mean like that the
you don't take it as something separate
from your sense of self I would think it
depends I guess yeah it could work but I
think what can also result in it's
basically mixing like the two different
approaches although they will individually arrive
although they will individually arrive
at the same either take your sense of
self and undermine it with the present
situation or with you or whatever or
even if you take this body in its extent
like this situation this body and their
death that in between will be where your
sense of self is not true yeah yeah so
if you if you set it up correctly it it
cannot remain unaffected in other words
but yes sometimes this will feel clearer
sometimes something else will feel clear
but the point is to keep trying to
pretty much revoke and maintain that
same direct principle inside of of that
undermines itself that doesn't require
the owner the master the center you send
yourself to be the witnessing observing
experiencing and so on you know it's
kind of stretched in between the two and
you realize well if either of these
changes my sense itself cannot remain thus it's
my sense itself cannot remain thus it's
not mine uh can it be my oh this this
sense itself is the master controller of
this great experience except that it's
neither the master not in control of it
so it's just not it's just that so what
is it then it doesn't matter what it is
what matters is that you keep confusing
it as your subject as your ownership and
so on remove that then you'll see what
it is
and I can give you an answer but then
because okay that's what itself is but
that's not the point the point is not to
find an answer to what cellphone not
self is the point is to remove that
ownership through through setting up
correctly that necessary basis for its
presence that cannot be your sense of
self at the same time yet your sense of
self always sits upon it
means again same this within this
feeling within the feeling this within
the mind that's when you need to have
the right view for that as well
um but yeah you want to contemplate the
element of Earth you could either if you
accurately on some days will be more
accurate than on others but yeah collect
the element of Earth and see there's a
necessary basis this body until you get
that kind of you know
sort of converging point on your
feelings so to speak where it's kind of
neither here nor there
and then you might be your mind might
push you to provide more clarity more
answers for these for this phenomena but
that's like oh now you're over
tightening the strings
so just start to see these two things
and then restrain or refrain from all
the okay
this and that I was like yeah okay well
if if I see this sufficiently enough
those things will be recognized there on
their own because that's where they are
sometimes you might not be able to
recollect the element where accurately
so you start with your body situation
and then they send the element of Earth
through this body notice something left
right before or after
because while this body is seated here
the factual element of Earth the
solidity pertains to it while this body
is seated here
that's I mean that's exactly how a body
is defined for you through the degraded
resists to the degree that it's solid
independently and there you go that's already enough
and there you go that's already enough
of a degree for non-ownership of your
situation so what I do now yeah exactly tune that
so what I do now yeah exactly tune that
further and let it play for as long as
it endures
and when it stops during when it
disappears then set it up again so when
you say when it stops enjoying means
when you get distracted away so so then
then I I guess one way of describing
that it could be that you sort of get
you move back into a more particular
uh experiences yeah you fell off from
the band The General yeah this this
bigger when you hide it you either moved
into like too General
um
not necessarily mystical because the
level of the views but more like uh
abstract yeah
like you're not thinking Earth and stuff
but not on the base of the president
during body or you just fall onto the
you know here in the under where the
senses are and sense objects and then
just get absorbed into that
or even like you're see you you cease to
approach your body as a recognition of
your whole situation but you kind of end
up approaching it as particular
Sensations or parts of the body and so
on that you're kind of attending to so
that's again falling onto the level of
the sense objects yeah exactly you know
yeah the body as a whole the body as a
basis for this entire situation which it
did there the body posture I mean how
can you specifically
observe your body posture the only
reason you can observe specific parts of
your body posture is because you already
know what posture you're in
so it's quite the opposite from like the
body sweeping it's actually recognizing
the the as I said recollect the memory
of your posture the image the thought
that is there and that is factually here
preceding yourself
sorry I'm I mean yeah it was fun
I had to when you say this I always add
like that discernment will then be
uprooting send the sense of self yeah
because yeah unless it's doing that then
it's yeah you're not you're not
reflecting on the problem so because as
I said the more the clearer it becomes
this this is
the two simultaneous things
even if you don't specifically think
about the ownership and this and
approaching it it is being recruited
because it prevents you from owning the
it prevents you from owning the
Assumption of one experienced Center
self owner sometimes people mystify it
and say oh it's the Observer the pure
Consciousness the knower the this the
that it's just basically different
phrasing for the same thing I am
but that's not the way I never has been
so you want to see that doesn't matter
how lofty how remote how distant how
great that Observer of the knower might
feel would he be there if this situation is
would he be there if this situation is
not enduring the way it is out of your
hands pretty much no
that's with this this is
and that all-knowing Seer Noah
it's pretty much
to the same extent not not a bit more
not a bit less subjected to exactly same
things that all of this is subjected to
impermanence duka and unability
so then it doesn't matter how it feels
what matters is that it ceases to be
yours either way whether it feels coarse
or lofty that's itself coarse lofty
refined whatever Pleasant and pleasant
it's just a reflection of the same
principle that's here nothing else
and then that's the true I'm burning
basically because there is now
because there is now
no more of that assume Center that takes
all the weight on
a bit like
like you said the one of the other times
the more uh one sort of gets used to
this type of contemplation the less it
will be dissonant in regards to the sense of
be dissonant in regards to the sense of
security in the sense of selfish you
know what I mean like that it's it's
like it's like you know if something you
thought was so solid and so secure the
first time you realize that actually
it's just this flimsy House of Cards
it's like uh oh terrifying but now you
know if it's just a house of cards it's
a house of cards you don't expect it to
be anything else yeah you if you if you
throw again through graduate training
census Trend you actually stop fueling
stop adding more fuel to the fire of
passion aversion and ownership then yeah
the the more of the same recognition
that this house has is flimsy and it's
going to collapse the more you have it
the less unpleasant it will be so it was
unpleasant not because of the
recognition but because of your
emotional involvement with the House of
Cards dependence on it views refusal to
allow it to be otherwise out of bed
again Gertrude's sense of
ownership of the you know like the
self-centered experience no no but I
want it like this
the question is that even when the doubt
cannot deliver the principle anymore
because it's part of it it's within it
that's how you go beyond doubt by not
having ability to doubt exactly that
doesn't hinder the the basic Insight
anymore yeah yeah is it
yeah yeah is it
it's very bad to think that doubt is uh sort of
sort of
bad quality or um
it's unpleasant so people naturally then
like oh I must you know I just can't
bear this anymore so
it is a hindrance and from that point of
view it is a bad quality because it does
require kind of inadvertently stepping back into
kind of inadvertently stepping back into
that self-centered point of view that's
only when the doubt is possible
but if despite the doubt in face of a
doubting mind you still see this this is
that because it is such a fundamental
principle that if you develop it's efficient
that if you develop it's efficient
enough yeah doubt is obviously second to
it and you even now you can see how
doubt would be second to it but the
point is to keep having doubt included
within the principle when doubt is there
so the question is not to how not to
doubt the question is how to then
surmount the doubt with the same
principle of non-ownership
and then yeah when that it just becomes
impossible to to
put doubt to access that which precedes
it which is a necessary basis
then you might doubt other things and
then the doubt is a hindrance it will
still persist
in regard to this so that and we're
going to pressuring the mind trying to
get you to act to clarify to fill the
craving further but it can have a spill
outside in the same sense the conceit
gets left the sense of I am that's left
the degree of passion aversion that's
left cannot spill outside into that
previously assumed atavada and the the
sense of self-independent of these
Aggregates and this experience and
everything else the absolute master
control that's outside of all of this
that's inconsiderable you can have those
thoughts as an empty phrases pretty much
but all you see is this this and that
becomes meaningless thoughts
like shells of your previous beliefs so
to speak did you now you know that were
impossible and the only reason they were
there is because you didn't know it was
impossible you thought it was possible
he assumed possibility of being outside
of this experience as a whole
assuming you about assuming the
possibility of being outside of the five
ogregates
but when all you have is this body
within this body
mind within the mind
or body within the Earth
both within the body whichever way if
when you have that simultaneous
dependence it doesn't require you there
has no room for you
then there is an outside of that
and that's good news initially same as
you just said in terms of the House of
Cards having no outside will be scary
because you assume that's where the
freedom is but it's not if they were
outside there would be just another
thing you were subjected to
even boys think that you're subjected to
even bigger thing to use ability to
but only subjected to is this and this
this this is
which is all which is entire samsara if
left unchecked and uh
unchecked and uh
ignored
but I know sometimes people can also
think like
okay maybe they don't take it on that
level but they think or if I if I have
the right view this doubt would not
exist like doubting mind would not be
able to be there oh this is the deal
this is actually the opposite message
well yeah but it's like no no you're
still gonna have a doubt but the facts
are no longer well exactly you have a
discussion we had a few weeks ago yeah
yeah so so it says that the how far can
that doubt pivot the order that will not
be that that will be rained in yeah yeah
because again your situation remains you
can have the doubt of Mind as this is
you can have any hindrance with this
this is with this sensualities with this
it will is but we can't doubt that
principle well yeah you can say that but
you can still doubt whatever that turns
it is just to reckon and say while
you're doubting it
during basis it's a necessary basis for
that doubt so that doubt is not yours
there is no side of it
yeah so because doubt is always about
something there is something that you're
doubting yeah you cannot just have the
phenomenal doubt sitting there in the
vacuum so even from that point of view
it's intentional and as such there has
to be something that's doubted yeah so
on the necessity basically but it's just
that you put that craving and pressure
of that first
and that which is doubted second
and then it's endless so you can count
the principle
you can't you can take it as an object
and start doubting it yeah
even but that of course doesn't mean
that like when you start doubting it it took
like when you start doubting it it took
it as an object it ceases basically to
be seen as the actual principle
yeah but then somebody who has to have a
view would know that that is not an
equalizer the Right View I resume
what well what you just said
it's just an idea yes there is a
difference between thinking about a
principle and extrapolating it in an
idea which is very much something you
can doubt that's why you would ask the
max max the one who is not clear about
this that endures here and now is he
doubtful yes yes the one who is clear
can he be doubtful no
that's the point but yes if you lose the
clarity of this this on the present
basis and start thinking about it in terms of
and start thinking about it in terms of
abstract thoughts
then yeah that's that's not a principle
anymore although it's the principle it's
the the ingredients of the principle the
principle is only when your situation is
the basis of it where it's included when
it's felt when it's there yeah
kind of a limit but how far then you
could continue well if yeah if you have
understood that principle and developed
it to the extent necessary whereby you
realize oh yeah my mind can't turn to it
but it's ridiculous because I see that
doubt within the principle nothing can
change then yeah the mind will stop
trying to doubt it brass spot
brass spot
yeah each time is going to be cleaner
but only next time you'll see they can
be even cleaner you describe the um this
week where we're talking about it's like
a stretch every every time
like yeah yeah like like if your mind
sort of Falls onto the the senses or
goes into the abstractions yeah it's
almost like a mental stretch to hold on
this situation is a whole this body
element to Earth within it or whatever
this sense of self on the basis of this
present enduring situation of the senses
two simultaneous things
and then you fall from it sometimes just
too doubtful to begin with that means
maybe you're trying to forcefully
to set it up the point is to descend the
principle on account of what's already
enduring not do it on account of okay
now I shall see this because that's
always going to give rise to craving
yeah yeah so that's how you learn to
think without craving as well to intend
without craving
you attend on the basis of what's
already there same intended so to speak
so to start with the situation as a
whole and within that the student life
rather than starting so you start with
situation as a whole eye with what
you're attending but within that you
don't attend the next thing you discern
the origin of that attention that
simultaneously present so manasikara and
the yonis of it
so with this this is that's what that
means yeah